Guide to the Mary Coolidge Rentschler Collection 1793-2000 (bulk, 1875-1950) MS 2999
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Manuscripts and memorabilia
  - Subseries I.C. Gordon Sohn Rentschler (1885–1948) [GSR]
    In 1947 he was presented with the Belgian Order of the Crown, and in 1949 he was appointed Honorary Commander of the Most Excellent Order of the British Empire (CBE), both awards honored his work during World War II, the latter was awarded for his efforts in the Lend Lease program. (The correspondence suggests that he was awarded the CBE in 1947, but the medal was received posthumously by Mary C. Rentschler in 1949. The correspondence can be found in Box 16, Folders 18 & 20. The medals were removed to Boxes Mem-40 and Mem-41.) Similarly, he received certificates signed by New York City Mayor Fiorello LaGuardia (1941) and United States President Harry Truman (1946). (Removed to oversize print material Box 3). All of these letters, certificates, and medals reflect a life of public service as the leader of one of America's largest banking institutions. This is firmly underscored by the large number of condolence letters received by his wife and National City Bank at the time of his death in 1948. Correspondents include: Ralph S. Danon, Abraham Flexner, B. C. Forbes, James Forrestal, Bernard F. Gimbel, John D. Rockefeller, Alfred P. Sloan, Jr., Robert M. Sohngen, and Cardinal Spellman. Gordon Rentschler's death papers also include beautiful, illuminated testimonials from companies and institutions associated with him, as well as correspondence surrounding the creation of a Gordon S. Rentschler memorial professorship at Princeton University. (The death papers are in Boxes Man-18 & Man-19.)
    The documents demonstrate Rentschler's stature in the business world. However, this knowledge is balanced with a few other, more private artifacts in the collection. Rentschler's bible contains selected correspondence, such as the following letter from Mary C. Rentschler at the time of her first husband's death:
    "If it were not for friends like you, I do not know how I could go on. But I draw strength from the love I know you bore Ted—& that I feel you will always bear him—for that is the kind of friend you are, as he often told me. Ted's friendship with you was one of his most cherished possessions. I hope I may be allowed to keep it and guard it always. Most devotedly yours, Mary C. Atkins" (1923 January 30; The bible and letters are housed together in Box Mem-30).
    - Financial: Minutes, 1925 January 20-1944 September 21 (Offsite-box Man-14, Folder 13)
      Minutes of the George Adam Rentschler Company, Hamilton, Ohio.
    - Incorporation papers, 1904 October 11-1935 January 7 (Offsite-box Ovz-3)
      G. A. Rentschler Co., Hamilton, Ohio.
    - Financial: Legal agreement, 1928 November 28 (Offsite-box Man-14, Folder 14)
      Legal agreement transferring capital stock in the G. A. Rentschler Company from Henry A. Rentschler (father) to Peter E. Rentschler and Walter A. Rentschler (sons).
    - Stock certificates (GSR & MCR), 1935-1950 (Offsite-box 5, Box Mem-39)
      Cancelled Hamilton Corporation stock certificates made out to Mary C. Rentschler, gordon S. Rentschler, Frederick B. Rentschler, Helen R. Waldon.
    - Financial: Document, undated (Offsite-box Man-14, Folder 15)
      1) List of the stocks of Gordon S. Rentschler
      2) Distribution of the shares of the G. A. Rentschler estate
    - Financial: Book draft, 1919 September 1 (Offsite-box Man-14, Folder 16)
      Book draft about the Hooven Owens Rentschler Company, Hamilton, Ohio.
    - Financial: publication, 1919 (Offsite-box Man-14, Folder 17)
      Dummy book "Seventy Years of Growth: The Modern Development of Heavy Duty Engines," the Hooven Owens Rentschler Company, Hamilton, Ohio.
    - Financial: Correspondence, documents, 1923 December 1-1991 August 21 (Offsite-box Man-14, Folder 18)
      Specifications, price lists, sales and advertising correspondence for the Hooven Owens Rentschler Company and Niles Tool Works Company (predecessors to the Baldwin-Hamilton Company).
    - Financial: Document, 1946 October 15 (Offsite-box Man-14, Folder 19)
      Resolution of the George A. Rentschler Company honoring Thomas A. Dorsey as a lifelong employee of the company.
    - Correspondence, 1885 July 18-December 15 (Offsite-box Man-14, Folder 20)
      Correspondence from Joseph B. Hughes to George A. Rentschler Sr. re:
      1) birth of Gordon S. Rentschler
      2) castor patent
    - Correspondence, notebook, news clip, 1896 January 20-1922 November 4 (Offsite-box Man-14, Folder 21)
      Notebook and correspondence re: purchase and maintenance of the Rentschler farm, Hamilton, Ohio.
    - Correspondence, 1896 July 1 (Offsite-box Man-14, Folder 22)
      Letter from P. P. Hunter in Dresden, Germany, to Henry Sohn and George A. Rentschler Sr. in Hamilton, Ohio. Description of European vacation destinations, including pen illustrations.
    - Essays, 1897-1900 (Offsite-box Man-14, Folder 23)
      Essays by Robert P. Rentschler (high school, etc?).
    - Document, valentine, news clip, 1898-1903 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 1)
      Miscellaneous items from Robert P. Rentschler
      1) valentines to Helen R. Waldon and George A. Rentschler Sr.
      2) bithday greetings to Phoebe S. Rentschler
      3) news clippings re: RPR educational progress
    - Correspondence, circa 1898-1923 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 2)
      Correspondence and valentine from George A. Rentschler Jr., including
      1) his first letter
      2) valentine from GAR Jr. to his mother
      3) letter to his parents from Princeton University
      4) letter from Sweden re: European travel destinations
    - Document, 1898 April 25 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 3)
      Mayoral proclamation to organize a war committee in Hamilton, Ohio. Signatures of the committee members include Peter Schwab Sr., George P. Sohnigen, Adam Rentschler (i.e., George A. Rentschler Sr.?).
    - School reports, 1898-1907 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 4)
      Gordon S. Rentschler's school reports from Hamilton High School, Hamilton, Ohio, and Princeton University, New Jersey.
    - [Princeton material], 1907-1916 (Offsite-box Ovz-3)
      (1) Daily Princetonian, 1907
      (2) Western Association of Princeton Clubs, Chicago, 1916
      (3) Photograph of Isabella McCosh Infirmary, Princeton
    - Check, invoice, 1899 June 3-1910 April 4 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 5)
      Checks from Gordon S. Rentschler to "Republican News" and to GSR from Rentschler Bros. Also an invoice to GSR from James W. See, mechanical engineer, re: bed patents, Hamilton, Ohio.
    - Document, 1900 September 17 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 6)
      Front page of inscribed bible. From Phoebe S. Rentschler to her son, Robert P. Rentschler.
    - Correspondence, photograph, telegram, program, 1900 December 26-1912 February 6 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 7)
      Correspondence to Gordon S. Rentschler as student. Congratulations on Hamilton High School speech; Commencement program; correspondence from Dorothy McKinney; later correspondence from Helen M. Brant traveling across southwestern United States.
    - Essays, circa 1901-1903 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 8)
      School essays and speeches, hand- and typewritten by Gordon S. Rentschler, including farewell address to seniors at Hamilton High School (includes party expense list). Essays on "The Power of Influence," "Abraham Lincoln," "George Washington," and "Literature."
    - Greeting card, circa 1903-1907 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 9)
      Greeting cards and notes to (and from?) Gordon S. Rentschler.
    - Invitation, marriage announcement, news clip, circa 1903-1940 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 10)
      Marriage announcement of Mary Ridgely to Gordon Taylor Hughes, 1903. 1940s press clipping explaining that Gordon S. Rentschler was named after Gordon T. Hughes.
    - Diary, 1904 August 3-14 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 11)
      Travel diary to the St. Louis World's Fair, Missouri. Written by either Robert P. Rentschler or Gordon S. Rentschler. Members of the trip included Thomas A. Dorsey, Howard See, and Frederick B. Rentschler.
    - Correspondence, 1908 March 11 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 12)
      Letter from new editor of the Daily Princetonian, Grant Straus, to Gordon S. Rentschler, outgoing editor, thanking him for his guidance.
    - Correspondence, 1908 November 27 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 13)
      Social correspondence from Alice? in Cincinnati, Ohio, to Mabel Dorsey in Hamilton, Ohio (wife of Thomas A. Dorsey).
    - Correspondence, 1909 August 16 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 14)
      Photocopy of a letter from Dr. Dan Millikin in Hamilton, Ohio, to Phoebe S. Rentschler? re: naming an automobile.
    - Draft of speech, 1911 November 4-1912 February 21 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 15)
      Gordon S. Rentschler draft of Princeton University reunion speech, 1912? Miscellaneous check and calculations.
    - Correspondence, 1912 March 26-1995 May 10 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 16)
      Photocopies of correspondence and I.O.U. re: sale of car by Gordon S. Rentschler and Frederick B. Rentschler for the Republic Motor Car Company, Hamilton, Ohio, to Charles (Carl) Bartels of Mosler Safe Company.
    - Correspondence, bound volume, 1916 January 14-February 21 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 17)
      Condolence letter from Louis D. Froelick, Princeton class secretary, to Phoebe S. Rentschler, upon death of Robert P. Rentschler; PSR reply. Bound resolution from 1906 class at Princeton University honoring RPR.
    - Correspondence, 1918 December 24 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 18)
      Letter from Sidney D. Waldon in Detroit, Michigan, to Gordon S. Rentschler in Hamilton, Ohio, praising him for his unsung WWI war effort, his fine character, and their friendship.
    - Correspondence, 1925 January 8-1956 September 21 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 19)
      Humorous correspondence between Henry Breckenridge and Gordon S. Rentschler upon the election of GSR to NCB. Also lists identifying people in a family photo (which family photo?).
    - Correspondence, telegram, news clip, 1925-1927 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 20)
      General correspondence from family and friends to Gordon S. Rentschler. Mainly thankyou letters for gifts received. Also list of major booksellers in Germany. Isabel Coolidge re: world stability.
    - Correspondence, 1927-1957 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 21)
      Letter from Gordon S. Rentschler to Thomas A. Dorsey in praise of Mary C. Rentschler, his fiancee, just prior to their marriage. Also an accompanying note from GSR's secretary, Alfreada Link, sending the letter to MCR.
    - Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Offsite-box Man-15, Folder 22)
      General corresponcence, mainly thankyou letters and requests for job assistance, including
      1) Roy Dickinson comical request for job as writer
      2) Helen R. Waldon for Lincoln auto
      3) Gift of watch from Charles A. Coolidge Sr. to GSR
    - Correspondence, 1929 January 5-1941 November 23 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 1)
      General correspondence to Gordon S. Rentschler:
      1) Peter E. Rentschler re: Rentschler finances
      2) Helen R. Waldon description of the Hamilton, Ohio farm (June 29, 1932); meeing King and Queen of United Kingdom (June 16, 1939); death of Henry A. Rentschler (1941).
    - Bound volume / testimonial, 1929 April 6 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 2)
      Tribute (bound volume) to Gordon S. Rentschler from his 1907 classmates at Princeton University upon his appointment as president of the National City Bank of New York.
    - Correspondence, document, 1929 April 26-1954 February 5 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 3)
      Correspondence to Gordon S. Rentschler, selected by Mary C. Rentschler. Mainly from colleagues in banking, politics, education, and medicine. Confidential memo re: Hearst finances; state of medical profession; Deeds birthday tribute by MCR; GSR to MCR re: WWII news.
    - Correspondence, 1930 June 26 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 4)
      Letter to Gordon S. Rentschler from Dean? re: 1753 lottery ticket for construction of Nassau Hall [Princeton University]. Donated to GSR?
    - Correspondence, 1931 July 31 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 5)
      Letter from Clarence H. Mackay to Gordon S. Rentschler re: transferral of a labrador puppy (called Deep River Diver) to GSR.
    - Correspondence, 1932 February 13 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 6)
      Letter from a Hamilton, Ohio factory worker to Gordon S. Rentschler describing his physical problems that prevent him from working.
    - Correspondence, 1932 June 3-24 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 7)
      Correspondence between Jack Howard, Lee Olwell, and James M. Cox re: "Rentschler Badge" awarded to Gordon S. Rentschler for service in breaking up gang of horse thieves in Butler County, Ohio.
    - Gordon S. Rentschler medal, 1932 June (Offsite-box 5, Box Mem-37)
      Badge inscribed "Special Officer" awarded to Gordon S. Rentschler for service in breaking up a gang of horse thieves in Butler County, Ohio (see letter in Box Man-16, Folder 7).
    - Correspondence, 1932 August 8 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 8)
      Letter from W. H. Reinhart, Commissioner, Division of Conservation, to E. A. Deeds re: Ohio State Coon Farm. A loose note was included in this file as possibly connected with letter; includes annotated racist comment.
    - Correspondence, 1932 December 22-24 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 9)
      Correspondence between William F. Carey and Gordon S. Rentschler re: gift of limited edition book sent to GSR.
    - Document, publication, 1933-1935 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 10)
      Moisie Salmon Club, Canada, score sheet of fish caught. Also fish and game laws of New York State.
    - Correspondence, 1934 December 20-24 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 11)
      Christmas greetings and thanks from friends of Gordon S. Rentschler: E. H. Brinker of General Machinery Corp., Hamilton, Ohio, and? of New York City.
    - Correspondence, 1938 October 12 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 12)
      Letter from Charles Nagel in St. Louis, Missouri, to Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City, thanking him for wine shipment.
    - Correspondence, 1942 December 28 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 13)
      Letter from E. A. Deeds to Gordon S. Rentschler expressing serious concern for the latter's health.
    - Correspondence, 1943 August 26 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 14)
      Letter from L. Birdsong to Gordn S. Rentschler re: reunion picnic for General Machinery Corporation employees, Hamilton, Ohio?
    - Correspondence, 1944 November 29 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 15)
      Letter from Faith A. Witter to Gordon S. Rentschler, includes
      1) theater arrangements
      2) The Ritz, Boston, agreeing to cash checks after hours as GSR is her stepfather
      3) Lowell lectures
    - Correspondence, 1945 March 19 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 16)
      Letter from Mrs. Randolph (Mary?) Burgess to Gordon S. Rentschler. Burgess writes as a professional statistician and creator of growth/weight charts. Explains the importance of teaching children personal responsibility, as well as intellectual knowledge.
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 17)
      Condolence letter from Dr. Burton J. Lee to Gordon S. Rentschler upon the death of Sidney D. Waldon.
    - Correspondence, 1946 November 14-1947 September 26 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 18)
      Correspondence re: award to Gordon S. Rentschler of the Order of the Crown of Belgium. Correspondents include E. Van Der Heist, Robert Pearce, and Baron Silvercruys.
    - Gordon S. Rentschler Belgian Order of the Crown (medal), circa 1946 (Offsite-box 5, Box Mem-40)
      Medal of Commander of the Order of the Crown, awarded to Gordon S. Rentschler from Charles, Prince of Belgium, for his work during WWII.
    - Correspondence / poem, 1947 January 8 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 19)
      Copy of Christmas poem written by W. Cameron Forbes for the Tavern Club and sent to Gordon S. Rentschler.
    - Correspondence, telegram, 1947 May 23-1949 March 10 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 20)
      Materials concerning Gordon S. Rentschler's appointment as Honorary Commander of the Most Excellent Order of the British Empire (CBE). Including letter from H. R. F. Brett to Mary C. Rentschler on behalf of deceased husband.
    - Gordon S. Rentschler Commander of the British Empire (medal), circa 1947-1949 (Offsite-box 5, Box Mem-41)
      Medal awarded to Gordon S. Rentschler by King George VI for his assistance to Great Britain during WWII (CBE--Honorary Commander of the Most Excellent Order of the British Empire). (See Box Man-16, Folder 20, for details.)
    - Correspondence, document, 1948 January 15 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 21)
      Proposal for a study of education and training for business by Wyman P. Fiske. Sent to Gordon S. Rentschler.
    - Christening certificates, Rentschler family, Hamilton, Ohio, 1884-1894 (Offsite-box Ovz-3)
      Christening certificates for Robert P. Rentschler, Gordon S. Rentschler, Frederick B. Rentschler, Helen D. Rentschler, and George A. Rentschler.
    - Children's books, 1888-1889 (Offsite-box 3, Box Mem-28)
      Four children's books: "A Snow Baby" and "Christmas Tree Fairy" for Gordon S. Rentschler; "Round the Hearth" for Robert P. Rentschler; and "Fun and Frolic" (not dedicated).
    - Gordon S. Rentschler autograph book, 1893 (Offsite-box 3, Box Mem-29)
      Autograph book froom Phoebe S. Rentschler to her son, Gordon S. Rentschler.
    - Gordon S. Rentschler bible, misc. personal correspondence, gold tooth filling, circa 1896-1935 (Offsite-box 3, Box Mem-30)
      Bible of Gordon S. Rentschler (1896). Childhood letter and poem by MCR (circa 1900-1904); correspondence to GSR from MCR upon death of husband and boys (1923); Charles A. Coolidge Sr. to GSR; valentine from Faith A. Witter; gold tooth filling.
    - Robert P. Rentschler flower book, 1898 April 5 (Offsite-box 3, Box Mem-31)
      School composition book about plants, seeds, and flowers, by Robert P. Rentschler, containing pressed flowers.
    - Peter Schwab brewery beer bottle, circa 1900 (Offsite-box 4, Box Mem-32)
      Bottle from the Peter Schwab brewery in Hamilton, Ohio.
    - Confirmation certificates, Rentschler family, Hamilton, Ohio, 1900 (Offsite-box Ovz-3)
      Confirmation certificates for Robert P. Rentschler and Gordon S. Rentschler.
    - Gordon S. Rentschler High School Diploma, Hamilton, Ohio, 1903 June 9 (Offsite-box Ovz-3)
      Hamilton High School diploma for Gordon S. Rentschler.
    - Gordon S. Rentschler Princeton yearbooks and publication, 1905-1916 (Offsite-box 4, Box Mem-33)
      Publications/programs from Princeton University:
      1) The Daily Princetonian dinner program, 1905, 1907
      2) Princeton Class Day publication (yearbook?), 1906, 1907
      3) Western Association of Princeton Clubs dinner program
    - Frederick B. Rentschler High School Diploma, Hamilton, Ohio, 1905 June 13 (Offsite-box Ovz-3)
      Hamilton High School diploma for Frederick B. Rentschler.
    - Princeton University publication, 1907 (Offsite-box 4, Box Mem-34)
      The Princeton Bric a Brac, published by the Class of 1907. Belonged to Frederick B. Rentschler.
    - Gordon S. Rentschler ephemera, 1778, 1910-1943 (Offsite-box 3, Box Mem-27)
      Various membership and identification cards, including gun license: postal telegraph cable company cards; 40-dollar bill dated 1778; Young Men's Christian Association cards.
    - Miscellaneous: scrapbook contents, 1929-1948 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 22)
      Scrapbook belonging to Gordon S. Rentschler. Mainly invitations, ephemera, and news clippings re: Forbes magazine 30th Anniversary banquet in honor of foremost business leaders, 1947. Also jewelry theft, 1929.
    - Gordon S. Rentschler medal re: Huey Long, 1933 August 26 (Offsite-box 5, Box Mem-38)
      Medal probably awarded to Gordon S. Rentschler. Note in box reads "Medal struck in memory of the wash-room episode, Aug. 26, 1933 on Long Island when some 'hero' socked the 'Kingfish' Huey Long in a much needed retribution."
    - Miscellaneous: document, 1933 September 23 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 23)
      Copy of a document sent by Charles Penrose (a Princeton classmate of Gordon S. Rentschler's) to his son, future Princeton freshman Julian d'Este Penrose. The document describes changes since he was a freshman in 1903.
    - Miscellaneous: program / menu, 1938 March 4 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 24)
      Cuban Organization of the National City Bank of New York banquet menu. Banquet in honor of NCB President, Gordon S. Rentschler, in Havana, Cuba.
    - Miscellaneous: invitation, 1939 June 8-10 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 25)
      Reception invitation for the New York World's Fair, 1939, from its president and Mrs. Whalen to Gordon S. Rentschler and Mary C. Rentschler. The reception was in honor of King George VI and Queen Elizabeth. Copy of acceptance telegram from the Rentschlers.
    - Certificate from New York City Mayor Fiorello LaGuardia, 1941 May 28 (Offsite-box Ovz-3)
      Certificate from New York City Mayor Fiorello LaGuardia appointing Gordon S. Rentschler a member of the Mayor's Business Advisory Committee.
    - Certificate from U.S. Secretary of the Navy, 1942 June 15 (Offsite-box Ovz-3)
      Certificate to Gordon S. Rentschler from U.S. Navy for WWII work. Signed by Frank Knox, Secretary of the Navy; Ernest J. King, Admiral, U.S. Navy; Commandant of the Marine Corps; and ? Commandant of the Coast Guard.
    - Miscellaneous: program / menu, 1943 January 29 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 26)
      Program/menu for Princeton Library Trustees dinner.
    - Miscellaneous: program, 1945 June 19 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 27)
      Program for dinner in honor of General of the Army, Dwight D. Eisenhower, at the Waldorf-Astoria.
    - Miscellaneous: program, 1945 September 9 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 28)
      Dinner program in honor of the Admiral of the Fleet, Chester W. Nimitz, Waldorf-Astoria.
    - [Scrapbook], 1945-1947 (Offsite-box Ovz-3)
      Gordon S. Rentschler scrapbook:
      1) Whimsical map of MIT, 1945
      2) Newspaper and magazine articles re: Forbes Magazine 50th Anniversary celebration of the 50 most successful U.S. business leaders, November 1947
    - Miscellaneous: program, 1946 January 1 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 29)
      Bicentennial Announcement, Princeton University, 1746-1946.
    - Miscellaneous: bound volume, 1946 February 2 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 30)
      Testimonial from New York Chapter, American Institute of Banking, conferring honorary membership upon Gordon S. Rentschler.
    - Miscellaneous: bound volume, 1946 March 15 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 31)
      Program for a dinner in honor of Winston S. Churchill, Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, New York City.
    - Certificate from U.S. President Harry S. Truman, 1946 May 15 (Offsite-box Ovz-3)
      Certificate from U.S. President Harry Truman to Gordon S. Rentschler for his WWII war relief work.
    - Certificate from Forbes Magazine of Business, 1947 (Offsite-box Ovz-3)
      Forbes Magazine of Business certificate awarded to Gordon S. Rentschler as one of the 50 foremost business leaders in the U.S.
    - Miscellaneous: program, 1949 April 7 (Offsite-box Man-16, Folder 32)
      Program for a dinner honoring Air Force crew members for the first non-stop flight around the world, Fort Worth, Texas. (GSR deceased by then.)
    - Roll of Citicorp Board of Directors, 1987 (Offsite-box Ovz-3)
      A poster listing the Citicorp Board of Directors, 1910-1987.
    - Gordon S. Rentschler Ex Libris stamp, undated (Offsite-box 6, Box Mem-51)
    - Gordon S. Rentschler misc. magazines, 1927-1947 (Offsite-box 4, Box Mem-35)